<?xml version="1.0"?>
<configuration>
	<placeholders>
		<placeholder id="template_name">Database to Database Account Migration</placeholder>
	</placeholders>
	<sections>
		<section id="use_case">
I want to migrate a large set of accounts from one database to another.

This Template should serve as a foundation for the process of migrating accounts from Database A to Database B, it also provides the ability to specify the desired behavior with a filtering criteria when an account already exists in the Database B.

This Template leverages the [Batch Module](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing).
The batch job is divided in *Process* and *On Complete* stages.
Migration process starts from fetching all the existing Accounts that match the filter criteria from Database A.
On *Process* stage will create / update the accounts in Database B. In addition, it performs a lookup and assigns Account Representatives using the zip code of the source Account.
Finally during the *On Complete* stage the Template will show statistics of the data transfer in the studio console and send out a notification email with the results of the batch execution. 
		</section>
		<section id="considerations">
<![CDATA[
**Note:** This particular Anypoint Template illustrates the migration use case between two Databases, thus it requires a Database instances to work.
The Anypoint Template comes packaged with a SQL script to create the DB table that it uses. 
It is the user responsibility to use the scripts to create the tables in an available schema and change the configuration accordingly.
The SQL script files can be found in [src/main/resources/](../master/src/main/resources/)

This template is customized for MySQL. To use it with different SQL implementation, some changes are necessary:

* update SQL script dialect to desired one
* replace MySQL driver library (or add another) dependency to desired one in [POM](pom.xml)
* update Database Config to suitable connection instead of `db:my-sql-connection` in global elements (config.xml)
* update connection configurations in `mule.*.properties` file
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_cloudhub">
<![CDATA[
Once your app is all set and started, supposing you choose `db2dbaccountmigration` as domain name to trigger the use case, you just need to hit `http://db2dbaccountmigration.cloudhub.io/migrateaccounts` and report will be sent to the emails configured.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="running_on_standalone">
<![CDATA[
After this, to trigger the use case you just need to hit the local HTTP Listener Connector on the port you configured in your file. If this is for instance, `9090` then you should hit: `http://localhost:9090/migrateaccounts` and this will run the migration process and send the batch process statistics to the email addresses configured.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="application_configuration">
		<![CDATA[
**HTTP Connector configuration**
+ http.port `9090`

**Batch Aggregator configuration**
+ page.size `1000`

**Database Connector configuration**
+ db.a.host `localhost`
+ db.a.port `3306`
+ db.a.user `user-nameA`
+ db.a.password `user-passwordA`
+ db.a.databasename `dbnameA`

**Database Connector configuration**
+ db.b.host `localhost`
+ db.b.port `3306`
+ db.b.user `user-nameB`
+ db.b.password `user-passwordB`
+ db.b.databasename `dbnameB`

**SMTP Services configuration**
+ smtp.host `smtp.gmail.com`
+ smtp.port `587`
+ smtp.user `email%40example.com`
+ smtp.password `password`

**E-mail Details**
+ mail.from `batch.migrateaccounts.migration%40mulesoft.com`
+ mail.to `your.email@gmail.com`
+ mail.subject `Batch Job Finished Report`

]]>
		</section>
		<section id="api_calls">
		<![CDATA[
This section is not relevant for this use case.
]]> 
		</section>
		<section id="default_endpoints_xml">
		<![CDATA[
This is the file where you can find the inbound and outbound sides of your integration app.
This Template has only an [HTTP Listener Connector](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/HTTP+Listener+Connector) as the way to trigger the use case.

$H$H# Inbound Flow
**HTTP Listener Connector** - Start Report Generation

+ `${http.port}` is set as a property to be defined either in a property file or in CloudHub environment variables.
+ The path configured by default is `migrateaccounts` and you are free to change it for the one you prefer.
+ The host name for all endpoints in your CloudHub configuration should be defined as `localhost`. CloudHub will then route requests from your application domain URL to the endpoint.

Flow *triggerFlow* executes a [Batch Job](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing) defined in *businessLogic.xml*, which handles all the migration logic.
This flow has Exception Strategy that basically consists of invoking the *defaultChoiseExceptionStrategy* defined in *errorHandling.xml* file.
]]>
		</section>
		<section id="default_business_logic_xml">
		<![CDATA[
Functional aspect of the Template is implemented in this XML, directed by one flow responsible of excecuting the logic.
This file contains a [Batch Job](http://www.mulesoft.org/documentation/display/current/Batch+Processing) which handles all the migration logic.
]]>
		</section>
	</sections>
</configuration>
